So you just saw that if you add two series together and
你刚刚看到 如果把两个索引值不同的 Series 相加
if the indexes don't match, NaN will be filled in.
其结果就是 NaN
Now, in a lot of cases, I might not want NaN or
但在大多数情况下 我可能不希望
not a number to show up in my resulting series.
输出的 Series 中出现 NaN 或非数字
So if I didn't want the NaNs to be included, how would I deal with that?
所以 我怎样才能使结果中不出现 NaN？
For questions like this there's almost a way to do what you want with Pandas, but
针对此类问题 在 Pandas 中几乎总能找到相应的解决方法
it can be a bit tricky to figure out what that way is.
但要找到这个方法可能比较困难
One thing I might try is doing a Google search for pandas remove missing values.
我的方法就是在 Google 搜索 Pandas 如何删除缺失值
The second result, dropna looks promising.
第二个搜索结果是 dropna 看起来不错
The first thing I noticed about this documentation is that it operates on
我在文件中发现的第一点是
DataFrames, not series.
它在DataFrame上运行 而不是 Series
You'll learn about DataFrames next lesson.
你会在下一节课中学到DataFrame (Dataframe)
Now the documentation for pandas isn't always perfect.
Pandas 的文件有时会有不足之处
When I saw this result, I wondered if dropna would work on a series as well.
当我看到这个文件时 我在想 dropna 是否也可以在 Series 上使用
I decided to try it and it runs out it did.
我决定试一下 结果是可以的
This documentation also refers to an axis.
这个文件还提到了数轴 (axis)
Again, this is something you'll learn about in the next lesson.
这个你也会在下节课中学到
For now, the fact that this function is emitting labels where some or
目前来看 这个函数消除部分或全部缺失数据标签
all of the data are missing sounds promising.
的功能听起来就很不错了
So I'll try saving the result of this addition to the variable sum result and
所以我试着把加法的结果保存至变量的 sum_result
then I'll run sum_result.dropna.
然后 我运行 sum_result.dropna
And sure enough, I get a new series where all missing values are removed.
我得到了一个缺失值被删除的新 Series
There's actually a few different ways you could solve this problem in pandas.
在 Pandas 中 解决这个问题还有其它方法
For example,
例如
there's a way to treat missing values as zero before the addition.
可以在进行加法计算前将缺失值视为 0
So then the result of adding these two series would have value 1 for
这样以来 两个 Series 相加后
index a, since there's an assumed zero in series 2.
索引 a 的结果就是 1 因为 Series 2 中的这个值为 0
See if you can figure out how to do this.
看看你能否用这个方法解决这个问题
If you find a third solution to the problem of NaNs, that's great as well.
如果你能找到解决 NaN 问题的第三种方法 那也很好
Now figuring things out like this by Googling can be very challenging, but
通过 Google 搜索来解决此类问题可能比较难
it's also very important.
但也非常重要
Pandas has a lot of functionality, and
Pandas 有很多功能
this course won't be able to cover all of it.
这节课无法讲解所有功能
If you don't find what you're looking for
如果不能马上找到你需要的功能
right away, try a few different queries.
你可以尝试一些其它的查询方法
If you get stuck, you can always watch the solution video.
如果你无法解决这个问题 可以直接观看解答视频
You can use the programming quiz on the next screen
你可以利用下一个屏幕中的编程测试
to test out whether your solution is working.
来检查你的解决方案是否有效